When we were learning that response in design, we saw that
a common pattern was to use the master detail flow, which
is what were going to use for sunshine. Here are the
tablet mocks. We have a list of forecasts on the left, and
then for the selected item, we see the detail pane on
the right. This applies for a seven inch and ten inch tablets.
Both portrait and landscape orientations. In portrait mode, the columns are
just a little bit narrower, but it's still a two pane UI.
In terms of implementation, all of this will be under the
main activity. Then on the left, we have the forecast fragment.
And then on the right, we have the detail fragment. On
the phone, we would still have the main activity with the list
of forecast. And then selecting an item would still launch the
detail activity. Here's another way to visualize it. On the tablet, we
have two fragments side by side under one activity. And then
on the phone, we have the first activity containing the first fragment.
Selecting an item will launch the second activity containing the second
fragment. We're going to break this up into multiple coding tasks until
we build up the final layout. First we'll build up the
two pane UI for tablets. Then we'll hook up the communication
between the two fragments, so that's selecting an item replaces the
detail pane on the right. Then we'll learn how to show
an activated state on the currently selected item, so we know
what the details pane corresponds to. We'll also need to make
sure that the scroll position is maintained across
orientation changes. After that, we'll update the detail layout
so it's optimized for these wider screens. And
then we'll modify the adapter so that today's layout
looks like the other days. There's no special
today layout on the tablet. So hopefully it's clear
how we're going to approach implementing this tablet behavior and
we're going to step through it slowly, one by one